petizens.com 2010-11-20

# 

This policy is effective as of 1 June, 2008.

**Welcome to Petizens! We hope that you will have a great time using Petizens.com, a site for pet lovers and their pets. Before you get started, we urge you to read the following important information. If you have any questions with regard to the information please email us at[info@petizens.com](mailto:info@petizens.com?subject=Question%20about%20Petizens%20privacy%20policy%2C).  **

**Petizens does not knowingly allow children under the age of thirteen (13) to register for Petizens.com. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to register for Petizens.com or send any information about yourself to us.**

**1\. Our Privacy Principles**

We created Petizens.com to allow you to share information about pets with your family, friends and people around you. While doing so, protecting your privacy is extremely important to us. Our privacy policy follows the following important principles:

§         **You control exactly what information is shared on the internet and what information is kept private.**

§         **We (Petizens) will never knowingly share your human name or email with anyone in anyway.**

**2\. The Information We Collect**

When you register for an account to become a member of Petizens.com, we will ask you some basic personal information. Some of the information we ask for is required in order to register an account, while other information is optional. The required information includes your name, gender, email, and your hometown, state and country. If you are a US or Canadian citizen, we will also ask for your ZIP code. The optional information includes information such as your year of birth, which languages you prefer using, and other information. 

When you register your pet we will ask you for additional information, including the name of your pet, the type of animal, breed and color of your pet, and when your pet was born.

When you enter Petizens.com we also collect your browser type and IP address. In addition we store certain information from your browser using “cookies”. A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer tied to information about the user. Petizens also use session ID cookies to confirm that users are logged in to Petizens.com. These cookies terminate once the user closes the browser. By default, we use a persistent cookie that stores your login ID (but not your password) to make it easier for you to login when you come back to Petizens.com. You can remove or block this cookie using the settings in your browser if you want to disable this convenience feature. Be aware, however, that some parts of Petizens.com may not function properly if you disable cookies.

When you use Petizens.com, you will be able to form online relationships with other registered users, send and post messages, perform searches and queries, read and write articles, form groups, and transmit other information through various channels. Petizens will collect this information so that we can provide you with high-quality social networking services. This will, for example, allow you to view prior information or messages, or review your friends list, etc. 

**2\. How We Use the Information We Collect**

Petizens will never knowingly share your human name or email with anyone in anyway. However, we will display other information that you provide during the registration process and as you enter information into your human profile and that of your pet, and in connection with other services such as blogs, forums, etc. As such, Petizens will publish, for example, your hometown, state or country, and information you enter about your pet, as well as any entries you make in our forums and other areas of the site that allow you to upload information on our servers. Since Petizens will allow you to upload this type of information onto our servers, it is important that you remember that the information (photos, text, vides, etc.) will be available to anyone with internet access. As such, **it is very important that you never post any photo, video or information on Petizens that you do not want someone else to access**. For example, if you are writing a forum post about yourself, please remember not to reveal your name, email or home address or other similar information. Please be aware of this and also inform all members of you family who may use Petizens.com to be aware of this important reminder. 

If you choose to use our invitation service to tell a friend about Petizens.com, we will ask you for information needed to send the invitation, such as your friend's email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit Petizens.com. Petizens stores this information to send this one-time invitation, to register a friend connection if your invitation is accepted, and to track the success of our referral program, a program that will give you various benefits and rewards. Your friend may contact us at [info@Petizens.com](mailto:info@Petizens.com?subject=Please%20remove%20some%20information%20in%20your%20database%2C) to request that we remove this information from our database.

Petizens may send you service-related announcements from time to time through the general operation of the service. For instance, if a friend sends you a new message you may receive an email alerting you to that fact. You can control this notification service after you create your Petizens.com account. Petizens reserves the right to send you notices about your account even if you opt out of all voluntary email notifications. 

By using Petizens.com, you are consenting to have your personal data transferred to and processed in the United States and / or the People’s Republic of China. 

**Children Under Age 13**

**If you are under 13, please do not attempt to register for Petizens.com or send any information about yourself to us.**

Petizens does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13. Petizens does not knowingly allow such persons to register for a membership on Petizens.com. No one under age 13 may provide any personal information to or on Petizens.com. In the event that we learn that a child under age 13 has provided information to Petizens.com against our directions, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us immediately at [info@petizens.com](mailto:info@petizens.com?subject=Under%20age%2013%20user%2C). 

**Children Between the Ages of 13 and 18**

We strongly recommend that minors over the age of 13 ask their parents or legal guardian for permission before sending any information about themselves to anyone over the Internet. 

**Security**

Petizens takes appropriate precautions to protect your information. Your account information is located on a secured server behind a firewall. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number or your password), we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). (To learn more about SSL, go to [Wikipedia](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Sockets_Layer)). Because email and instant messaging are not recognized as secure communications, we request that you not send private information to us by email or instant messaging services. 

Although we do our best to protect your information, please remember that you post information on Petizens.com at your own risk. We cannot control the actions of other users with whom you may choose to share your pages and information. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that information you post on Petiznes.com will not be viewed by unauthorized persons. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on Petizens.com. You understand and acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of information may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other users have copied or stored your user Content. 

**Thank you for reading our Privacy Policy! Again, if you have any questions with regard to the information please email us at[info@petizens.com](mailto:info@petizens.com?subject=Questions%20regarding%20the%20privacy%20policy%2C).  **

**We hope you enjoy our site!**
